[Road to Success]
[星のように煌めく]
♪ And water the seeds ♪
♪ 清らかな泉で種を潤し ♪
♪ Let the good times glow ♪
♪ 喜びの時を咲かせよう ♪
♪ Let the good time ♪
♪ 穏やかな日々が流れてゆく ♪
♪ Let the good time flow ♪
♪ 喜びがどこまでも 続くように ♪
If you withdraw from school now,
今すぐ退学すれば
you can still save the last bit of dignity
あなたと舒教授の
[Withdrawal Application]
[退学届]
for yourself and Professor Shu.
名誉だけは守れるわ
[Goodbye, My Love]
[さらば 愛する人へ]
Professor Shu was such a good person,
舒教授みたいないい人が あの女のせいで
and he died because of her.
死んじゃったのよ
To get a PhD,
博士になりたいからって
you knowingly became a mistress.
人の男に手を出すなんて
Shameless.
恥知らずだ
If you don't want your teacher
指導教授が亡くなったあとまで
to be criticized after death,
後ろ指を指されたくないなら
withdraw from school.
退学しなさい
Heads,
表なら
I go ahead;
前へ進む
tails,
裏なら
I stay.
ここに残る
Wanxing.
星
A person's life
人の一生というのはな
is like a stream,
川の流れのようなものだ
only flowing forward.
ただ前へと流れていく
You can look back,
振り返ることはできても
but you cannot go back,
逆戻りはできない
because life itself is ahead.
人生はいつでも 前方へと続いている
If you haven't seen the path ahead yet,
もし今 進むべき道が 見えないのなら
I suggest that you come to Hongjing No. 8 High School.
宏景第八高校へ行ってみるといい
School is a healing place.
学校は人を癒やす場所でもある
[Grandpa, who loves you forever]
[愛するおじいちゃんより]
Go find yourself.
そこで本当の自分を取り戻しなさい
[Hongjing]
[宏景市]
We are now arriving at
まもなく
Hongjing Station.
宏景駅です
[Episode 1]
[第１話]
[Three months later]
[３ヶ月後]
Grandpa,
おじいちゃん
I've decided to listen to you
おじいちゃんの言う通り
and start over.
もう一度やり直すよ
This time,
今度は
I want to look forward in a different way
違うやり方で前を向いて
and live a carefree life.
気楽な干物人間でいようと思う
Grandpa,
おじいちゃん
I'm reporting to Hongjing No. 8 High School today.
今日 宏景第八高校に初出勤なの
Although I'm just a contract worker,
契約社員だけど
I'll work hard to keep this job.
頑張って残るから
Don't worry.
安心して
I'll be fine.
元気でやるよ
Bye.
行ってきます
Morning, Mr. Kang.
康おじいさん おはようございます
Morning, Wanxing.
晚星 おはよう
[Hongjing No. 8 High School]
[宏景市立第八高校]
Coming back to the place where my grandparents
再びおじいちゃんとおばあちゃんが
used to work and live,
働いて暮らした場所に来ると
it suddenly gives me a warm feeling.
不思議と心が温かくなる
It's simple
ただ穏やかで
and peaceful.
心地いい
Lin Wanxing,
林晚星
since you've decided to be a slacker,
干物人間でいようと決めたからには
just start now
今日からは
and enjoy it.
思いきり楽しまなくちゃ
[P.E. Department Office]
[体育科職員室]
[Teacher Employment Registration Form]
[教員採用入職申込書]
Lin Wanxing.
林晚星
Department of Psychology, Yongchuan University...
永川大学 心理学部
Ph.D?
博士なのか？
I dropped out.
中退です
That's still impressive.
それでもすごいな
Academic achievements.
研究実績は…
[Work-Related Academic Achievements]
[職務に関連する研究実績]
I currently have no academic achievements
今の仕事に関係する実績は
related to this job.
特にありません
With such a high degree as a Ph.D.,
博士課程まで進んだのに
Ms. Lin,
林先生
why do you want to be a sports equipment manager
どうしてうちの学校で
at our school?
体育用具の管理を？
I think this job is quite relaxed.
気楽な仕事だと思いまして
No matter what the position is,
どんな仕事も大切ですし
it's all contributing to education.
教育を支える仕事だと 思っています
The equipment room
用具室は
is right by the playground.
グラウンドの向こうだ
Follow me.
ついて来い
This is the smaller one.
こっちは小さい方だ
Take a look.
ほら
The bigger one is over here.
大きい方はこっちだ
[Sports Equipment Room]
[体育用具保管室]
Come on in.
さあ 入ろう
The room is a bit messy.
少し散らかってるけど
No one has been in here for a long time.
長いこと使われてなかったから
Be careful.
気をつけろ
Well,
まあ
the environment is not bad.
随分と「いい」環境ね
Ms. Lin,
林先生
this is your desk.
ここが君の席だ
Next,
じゃあ
I'll brief you on how things work
この倉庫のことを
in this storage room.
一通り説明するから
Take some notes.
メモしておいてくれ
Okay.
はい
Look.
ほら見て
All balls need to be organized.
ボールは全部ちゃんと 整理しておくんだ
For example,
例えば
these basketballs
バスケのボールとか
and soccer balls
サッカーボールとか
must be placed in this basket.
そういうのは全部このカゴに入れる
Tennis rackets need to be hung on the wall.
テニスラケットは 壁に掛けておくんだ
Don't put all the basketballs together.
バスケットボールは 一か所にまとめないで
Put them in different boxes.
箱を分けて入れてくれ
-Okay, Director Qian. -Keep the balls together and the rackets together.
- わかりました 銭主任 - ボールはボール ラケットはラケットで
These boxes
この箱も
are probably empty.
たぶん空だから
Put the shuttlecocks in them
シャトルを一個ずつ
one by one.
入れておいてくれ
Look at this.
見てみろ
It's a total mess.
めちゃくちゃだろ
Why is this pommel horse missing a leg?
この跳び箱 脚が一本ないな
The leg is over there.
ああ あそこにあるんだ
Reattach it later.
あとで付けておいてくれ
Stack the trampolines.
トランポリンも ちゃんと並べておいてな
Stack them neatly.
きれいに揃えて置いておけばいい
It's actually not too complicated.
まあ そんなに難しい仕事じゃない
It mainly requires
大事なのは
patience and care.
根気と気配りだな
Oh, right.
ああ そうだ
One more important thing.
もう一つ大事なこと
No equipment
用具は全部
can be borrowed
先生の許可なしで
without a teacher's permission.
貸しちゃダメだ
Even if borrowed,
貸す場合も
they must be returned the same day.
その日のうちに返却
Noted.
分かりました
All equipment needs a teacher's approval to be borrowed
用具は先生の許可が必要で
and must be returned the same day.
当日返却ですね
The probation period
試用期間は
is one month.
１か月だ
There's a PE department meeting tomorrow.
明日 体育教科の会議がある
You must attend.
必ず出てくれよ
Meeting attendance is counted towards your evaluation.
会議も出勤扱いだからな
Don't worry, Director Qian.
わかりました 銭主任
I will definitely take the initiative
全力で取り組んで
and accomplish this glorious and arduous task.
この大事な任務を必ずやり遂げます
Here are the keys.
じゃあ 鍵は預ける
I'll be going now.
私はこれで
Thank you.
お疲れさまでした
He's finally done talking.
やっと終わった
It's so dirty.
すごく汚いね
It needs a good cleaning.
ちゃんと片付けないと
[Knowledge is Boundless]
[学に終わりなし]
[Chen Jianghe, Former Football Team Forward]
[陳江河 元サッカー部の フォワード]
The door wasn't locked?
鍵が閉まってないじゃん
Why don't you...
あのさ
come down first?
先に降りない？
So,
君
why did you climb in through the window?
なんで窓から入るの？
What are you doing here?
お前こそ 何をしてんの？
Cleaning up.
掃除してるの
Then clean it well.
じゃあ きれいにしろ
And don't forget to close the door.
あと 戸締まりも忘れるな
Hey.
ねえ
What?
何だ
Don't you need to get a teacher's
サッカーボールを借りるなら
permission to borrow a football?
先生の許可は取ったの？
What does that have to do with you?
別に関係ないだろ
You got cleaning duty for not wearing your school uniform,
お前だって制服違反で 掃除させられてんのに
and now you want to snitch on me to a teacher?
今度は俺のことまで 先生にチクるつもりかよ
I don't need to snitch on you to a teacher.
先生にチクる必要なんてないわ
Then what do you want?
じゃあ 何なんだ
I want to tell you
そもそも勘違いしてるの
that I am a teacher.
私が先生よ
Are... are you really a teacher?
えっ マジで先生？
I'm new here.
今日から来たの
I'm in charge of this equipment room.
この用具室の担当よ
Since you're a teacher,
せ 先生なら
why were you acting so sneaky just now
なんでさっきコソコソしてたんだよ
and not locking the door?
しかも鍵開けっぱなしで
Who was the one being sneaky?
コソコソしてたのはどっちなの？
You are in charge of the sports equipment?
用具室の先生なんだ
Well...
じゃあさ
what sport are you in, teacher?
先生は何のスポーツをやってたんだ
Weightlifting.
ウエイトリフティングよ
Are you kidding me?
からかってるのか
Glad you know.
バレちゃった？
What grade and class are you in?
何年何組？
What's your name?
名前は？
I'm a senior in Class 5.
３年５組
My name is Qin Ao.
秦敖だ
Qin as in Emperor Qin.
秦は始皇帝の秦
Ao as in Tibetan Mastiff,
敖は獒犬の獒
without the "dog" component.
でも犬なしだ
Which teacher sent you?
どの先生に頼まれて来たの？
You're so annoying.
しつこいな
Then don't lend it to me.
貸さないならいい
Does this work?
その これならどうだ？
[100 free football equipment rentals]
[サッカー用品無料貸出券 100回分]
Just this?
これだけ？
I knew I got tricked.
やっぱりハメられてるな
This works too.
いや それで大丈夫
I'll lend you the ball.
ボールを貸すよ
What... did you say?
えっ 何だって？
I said,
だから
this works.
これは使えるってこと
Really?
マジかよ
Then who will sign it?
じゃあサインは？
But on one condition.
ただし条件がある
Come help clean up during the break.
休み時間に掃除を手伝って
You must return the ball today.
ボールは今日中に返して
Take it.
ほら 持ってきな
Climbing the window instead of using the door?
ドアがあるのに わざわざ窓から入るなんて
The students here surely have some personality.
なかなか個性的ね
A 100-use ball borrowing card?
ボール百回貸出券か
Interesting.
面白い
Having other students do the work for you?
他の生徒に代わりをやらせるなんて
[Sports Equipment Check-Out/Return Form]
[体育用具貸出管理表]
Mr. Tibetan Mastiff,
獒犬に犬なしくん
[100 free football equipment rentals]
[サッカー用品無料貸出券 100回分]
you have failed my trust.
先生の信頼を裏切ったわね
Hey.
みんな
Remember to lock the door when you're done.
終わったらちゃんと鍵閉めてね
This is a bad deal.
割に合わねえよ
Chen Jianghe is playing football,
陳江河はサッカーをしてるのに
making us do the work for him.
俺たちに雑用をさせるなんて
[Grade 12 Class 5]
[高校３年５組]
I'm going to clean house today!
今日こそこの手で門下の恥を討つ
Young Master!
若様
I've been so loyal to you!
俺はこんなに尽くしたのに
[Qin Ao, Former Football Team Forward]
[秦敖 元サッカー部の フォワード]
Young Heroine.
女侠よ
Trying so hard?
ずいぶん本気ね
I've been poisoned.
俺は毒にやられた
-Please help me. -Master Qin Ao.
- どうか解毒してくれ - 秦敖大侠は
Aren't you a martial arts master?
強いでしょ
Do it yourself.
自分で何とかしなさい
Boss, you were a bit overconfident.
兄貴 その自信はどこから来るんだ
Let's go.
行こう
Bao Xiaotian,
包小甜
tomorrow morning...
明日の朝
I'll have Xiaolongbao for breakfast.
俺 小籠包食べるから
I'll bring you some.
君の分も買っとく
Let's go, Yu Ming!
行くぞ 俞明
Excuse me,
すみません
is Qin Ao here?
秦敖君はいますか
[Lin Lu, Former Football Team Defender] [Yu Ming, Former Football Team Defender]
[林鹿 元サッカー部のセンターバック] [俞明 元サッカー部のディフェンダー]
[Qin Ao, Former Football Team Forward]
[秦敖 元サッカー部フォワード]
She's here for you?
おい 呼ばれてるぞ
Beautiful,
美人さん
do we know each other?
俺たち知り合いだっけ
What do you want?
俺に何の用？
Just as I thought.
やっぱりね
What?
何が？
When someone is introducing themselves,
自分の名前を名乗る時
they wouldn't say something like
普通は
"without the dog component".
獒犬に犬なしなんて言わないね
Today, a student with a buzz cut
今日ね 坊主頭の男子が
came to the equipment room
用具室に来て
and borrowed a football from me
この貸出券で
with this football lending card.
サッカーボールを借りたの
He said
その子は
his name is Qin Ao.
自分は秦敖だって言ってた
That Chen Jianghe! He...
陳江河のやつ…
He must've skipped class again
また授業をサボって
and snuck off campus to play football.
こっそり外でサッカーか
Don't be angry.
まあまあ
Boss, let's go.
兄貴 行こうぜ
I'll treat you to some meatballs.
拳頭母をおごるから
Chen-Jiang-He.
陳 江 河
Great ball! Great ball!
ナイス
Let's go!
行け
It's fine! Great ball!
ドンマイ ナイスボール
Don't rush!
焦るな
Pass it back! Pass it back!
回せ回せ 一回戻せ
Good ball!
ナイス
Pass it back!
回せ 回せ
-Move up! -Pass it!
- キープしろ キープ - 出したぞ
Over here!
こっち
Good shot!
ナイス
-Nice!
- ナイス
Defense!
守れ 守れって
Watch the ball!
ボールを見ろ
Let's go!
行け
♪ Two souls alike ♪
♪ 二つの魂が寄り添って ♪
♪ In the silent gravity ♪
♪ 静かな引力に導かれ ♪
♪ Cure my heart ♪
♪ 君のすべてで ♪
♪ With every part of you ♪
♪ 私の孤独な心を 癒してくれた ♪
♪ Our words flow ♪
♪ 言葉はそっと ♪
It's her.
彼女だ
♪ Like a gentle stream ♪
♪ 優しい川のように流れて ♪
♪ They glow like fireflies ♪
♪ 蛍のあかりが ♪
♪ Inside of a silky dream ♪
♪ 柔らかな夢へと舞い降りる ♪
♪ We talked the whole night, breeze away ♪
♪ 夜通し語れば 夜風も静かに眠ってゆく ♪
♪ Together we set out on a long journey ♪
♪ この長い道を ♪
♪ The endless journey ♪
♪ どこまでも歩いていこう ♪
♪ Gently smoothing away ♪
♪ そっと拭ってあげる ♪
♪ The hesitation in each other's eyes ♪
♪ その瞳に浮かぶ迷いを ♪
Help yourself.
どうぞ遠慮しないで
♪ Hearing the warmth inside ♪
♪ 胸の奥で秘められた 温もりを呼び覚ます ♪
♪ Life begins alone ♪
♪ 人生は一人で歩き始め ♪
♪ A road we walk alone ♪
♪ 孤独な道を進んでゆく ♪
♪ Until fate brings warmth ♪
♪ だけど運命が温もりを運び ♪
Thanks.
ありがとう
♪ To light our way back home ♪
♪ 帰る場所を照らしてくれた ♪
-Good ball! -Beautiful!
ナイス いいぞ
Go!
行け
Pass the ball now!
早くはたけ
-Nice! Nice! -Bring it inside!
- ナイス ナイス - 中だ 中
Don't rush!
焦るな
Didn't you tell me to help myself?
遠慮するなって
I meant,
そういう意味じゃなくて
I'd just share a little with you.
少し分けるってこと
Move!
空けろ 空けろ
Pass it!
出したぞ
Over here!
こっち
You know what?
知ってる？
Here, here!
こっち こっち
That boy
あの男子は
has been playing football there all afternoon.
昼からずっとサッカーしてる
He must be skipping class.
きっと授業をサボってるな
Hey, kid.
君
Hold on.
ちょっといいかな
What's your name?
お名前は？
That man is a scammer.
あの男は詐欺師だ
-You seem to be the only teacher around here. -I'm a scout for a football club.
- この辺りにいる教師は君だけのはずだ - スカウトです ずっと見てましたよ
I think you've got a lot of potential.
ものすごいポテンシャルを感じます
-This scammer is a pro. -You can register with our team.
- プロの詐欺師だ - 我がチームに移籍しませんか
-If he can't get him, he'll scam him out of his money. -If you join our team—I'm telling you...
- 人を誘拐できなきゃ金を巻き上げる - 加入していただきさえすればですね
-For example, personal loans. -Our club
- 個人ローンとか組ませて - 我がチームが
-ruining their families or something. -will give you professional training.
- 一家心中へと追い込むんだ - 特別な育成プログラムを用意します
This isn't part of my job.
それは私の業務外よ
Just sign this.
ここにサインするだけです
Bro, sign here.
さあ こちらへ
Wait a minute.
ちょっと待って
Who...
失礼ですが
Who are you?
どちら様でしょうか
I'm his sister.
この子の姉よ
My surname is Liu.
私は劉と申します
I'm with Yongchuan Hengjiu,
永川恒久の
a professional scout for their youth academy.
ユースチーム専属のスカウトです
Your brother is a football genius.
弟さんはサッカーの天才ですよ
I've been keeping an eye on him for a while.
先ほどからずっと見てました
My advice is
こちらとしてはですね
that he take a year off from school,
１年ほど休学して
play for our club,
うちのクラブで プレーしていただきたい
and become a star in the future.
将来はプロ選手も十分狙えます
As long as he joins our team,
うちのチームに入れば
he'll definitely have a chance to play in a professional league.
プロリーグも夢じゃありません
Does your club charge a fee?
そのクラブって費用はかかるの？
The 3-month training fee is 10,000 yuan.
３か月の研修費は20万円です
That's not much.
大した額じゃありません
Most families can afford it.
普通のご家庭でも十分負担できます
How about it?
いかがでしょう
If you're interested, we can talk more.
ご興味があれば詳しくご説明します
Since your club is so good,
そんなに素晴らしいクラブでしたら
I should tell the school
学校に報告して
and ask them to promote it.
ぜひ皆に紹介してもらわなきゃ
Wait a moment.
ちょっと待ってて
I'll go get my phone.
今スマホを取ってくる
No, no, no.
いえいえ
I have a meeting this afternoon.
午後に予定がありまして
I'll contact you later.
また改めて連絡します
Well...
あっ
Give me my pen.
ペンだけ返してください
We'll be in touch.
では失礼します
Scammers nowadays
最近の詐欺師って
are too blatant.
ずいぶん堂々としてるのね
Are you crazy?
何なんだよ あんた
You think I didn't know he was a scammer?
詐欺師だって分かってたよ
Don't I know what I'm capable of?
自分の実力くらい分かってるからな
Do you think youth training is about who's the best?
ユースなんて実力だけで 入れるってもんじゃない
It's about who bribes the coach the most.
結局はコーチにどれだけ 金を積めるかだろ
Being a professional player?
プロになるなんて
I've never had that kind of dream.
そんな夢見たこともねえよ
Wait a minute.
待って
What else do you want?
まだ何か
Return the ball.
ボールを返して
Chen-Jiang-He.
陳江河
Stop right there!
待ちなさい
Director Qian, you're here?
あっ 銭主任
♪ Every night ♪
♪ 毎晩 ♪
♪ I reach out to touch the starlight ♪
♪ 星の光に 手を伸ばす ♪
♪ Wandering through dreams with you ♪
♪ 君と夢の中を彷徨う ♪
♪ I follow the beat of my heart ♪
♪ 鼓動のリズムに乗せて ♪
♪ Like dust floating in the air ♪
♪ 宙を舞う塵のように ♪
Thank you for watching my bag.
荷物を見てくれて ありがとう
♪ Because of your love ♪
♪ 君の愛が ♪
You're welcome.
いえ
♪ I shine brilliantly ♪
♪ 私を輝かせる ♪
How did you know I'm a teacher?
でもなぜ私が先生だと分かったの？
Do we know each other?
知り合いだったっけ？
No.
いや
But...
でも
we do now.
でも今知り合った
[Receive Money by QR Code]
[ＱＲコード決済]
Sorry.
ごめんなさい
I don't just add anyone on WeChat.
知らない人と連絡先は 交換しないの
[Receive Money by QR Code]
[ＱＲコード決済]
Why are you asking me for money?
これ何のお金？
Storage fee.
荷物預かり代
♪ I caught your eyes ♪
♪ 君のまなざしを見つけた ♪
♪ On the summer night ♪
♪ あの夏の夜に ♪
[Receive Money by QR Code]
[ＱＲコード決済]
[Pay to Individuals]
[個人への支払い]
♪ A star that glows so bright ♪
♪ 眩しく輝く星のようだった ♪
What a day.
今日は一体何なのよ
What kind of people have I been running into?
変な人ばっかり
♪ A spark in my heart ♪
♪ 胸に灯る小さな火は ♪
Charging a storage fee just for watching a bag?
荷物を見ただけで 預かり代って…
♪ Disappear in my dream, secretly ♪
♪ 夢の中へ そっと消えてゆく ♪
Mom.
ママ
I'll help you carry this.
荷物を手伝うよ
Thank you.
ありがとうね
You're welcome.
いいよ
Do you like our new house?
新しいおうちが好き？
I do.
好きよ
You can make new friends tomorrow.
明日から友達ができるよ
-The new tenants moved in so quickly? -Okay. I'm so happy to move.
- 新しい入居者 もう来たのね - やった 引っ越しって最高
[One and a Half Years Ago, UK]
[１年半前 イギリス]
Jason, don't rush! Wait for me!
杰森 慌てるな 待ってろ
I entrusted my child to you.
息子をあなたに託したのに
Did you really take good care of him?
本当に守ってくれたの？
I'm sorry.
すまない
[Are you going back to China after graduation?]
[卒業したら帰国するのか]
[Thank you. In the UK,]
[ありがとう 君はイギリスで]
[you're the first friend to send me a gift.]
[初めてプレゼントを 送ってくれた友達だ]
[I'm serious. I'll send you a gift later. Remember to get the package.]
[冗談じゃないよ 今度プレゼント 送るから 受け取ってね]
[If anything's bothering you, you can always tell me.]
[辛いことがあったら 何でも相談して]
[My major is psychology anyway. At least I can talk to you]
[一応 心理学専攻だし 話し相手にはなるよ]
[and help you get to know more about yourself.]
[自分の心とも もっと向き合ってみよう]
[What do you mean?]
[どういう意味？]
[You know what? Pain is a brain protest.]
[知ってる？痛みって 脳からのそＳＯＳなのよ]
[To show that the line between goodwill and manipulation is only a thin layer of candy wrapper]
[善意と支配は紙一重だと 証明するため]
[There's something wrong with the candy you gave me last month, right?]
[先月くれた飴 問題があるのか]
[I'll eat it properly]
[ちゃんと食べる]
[I hope they can help ease your academic stress. Don’t waste them.]
[学業のストレスが楽になると いいね 無駄にしないでね]
[I immediately ate one. It tasted pretty good.]
[さっそく一つ食べた 旨かった]
[I'm glad you received it. Do you feel better now?]
[届いてよかった 元気出た？]
[I hate you.]
[お前なんか嫌いだ]
[Before I knew it, it was already New Year’s. How was your day today?]
[気づけばもう新年だね 今日は元気に過ごせた？]
Spade Q,
スペードのＱ
did you kill Jason?
お前が杰森を殺したのか
[One payment today]
[本日の入金 １件]
[Transaction Details]
[取引明細]
[Contact] [Lin Wanxing]
[連絡先][林晚星]
[Lin Wanxing]
[林晚星]
[WeChat Pay]
[WeChat Pay]
[WeChat]
[WeChat]
[Search]
[検索]
[Searching Contacts]
[連絡先を検索中]
[Slack Superstar]
[干物見習い]
[Add]
[友達申請]
[Send]
[送信]
[Sending]
[送信中]
[Slack Superstar]
[干物見習い]
Lin Wanxing.
林晚星
Are you Spade Q?
スペードのＱは 君なのか
[Hongjing No. 8 High School]
[宏景市立第八高校]
I'm Ms. Sun.
孫と申します
I heard that you
林先生って
are a top student from Yongchuan University.
永川大学の秀才だって聞きましたよ
The previous guy, Mr. Li, didn't even know how to use a computer.
前の李先生なんて パソコンも使えなくて
The whole equipment room was a mess.
用具室がもう大混乱でしたから
It seems the equipment room doesn't really need a computer.
用具室って そんなにパソコンを使いますか
Here.
さあさあ
I brought some snacks.
お菓子を持ってきたので
Let's share.
皆さんで召し上がってください
You're Ms. Lin, right?
林先生ですよね
Try this.
これどうぞ
-Thank you. -It's very delicious.
- ありがとうございます - とてもおいしいです
-And this. -Sorry.
- これもどうぞ - すまない
Sorry. I'm sorry.
すまないな
I'm late.
遅れちゃった
The principal called me over
校長に呼ばれててな
to get a new notice from the Education Bureau.
教育局から新しい通知が来たんだ
Sorry for
遅くなって
being late.
悪かったな
Everyone, stop what you're doing.
みんなちょっと手を止めてくれ
I'll read this document to you.
この通知の話だけしておくぞ
[Agent]
[不動産屋さん]
Notice from the Hongjing Education Bureau
宏景市教育局からの通知
on Further Strengthening
学校体育活動の
and Improving School Sports Work.
さらなる強化と改善について
Sorry.
すみません
It's my agent calling.
不動産屋からです
Put it on mute during the meeting.
会議中はマナーモードな
Just tell us directly.
単刀直入に言ってくださいよ
What exactly does this new notice say?
結局その通知って何なんです？
It's mainly about Hongjing City's
簡単に言うとだな
strong push
わが宏景市がサッカーに
to develop football.
力を入れるって話だ
So this year's Youth Super League—
だから今回のユーススーパーリーグ
our No. 8 High School
我々八高も
has to take part.
出場しなきゃならない
Haven't we been out of the Youth Super League for years?
ユーススーパーリーグって 何年も出てなかったですよね
Why are we joining now?
今さら出るんですか
"The all-round development of students in moral, intellectual, and physical education."
知育も徳育も体育も
We must focus on it,
全部大事だからな
especially sports.
特に体育だ
But our football team hasn't played for 2 years.
でもうちのサッカー部は ２年もまともに活動してないですよ
Can they do it?
大丈夫ですか
If we go, we'll just be eliminated in the first round.
出たところで 一回戦負けじゃないですか
You're selling yourselves short
すぐ弱気になる
and giving up before even trying.
やる前から逃げ腰
Look at you!
情けないな奴だ
The school leaders are very supportive of us.
学校もちゃんと応援してくれてる
The principal told me repeatedly that
校長にも言われてるんだ
if we have any difficulties or ideas,
困ったことがあったら
we should just mention them to him.
何でも相談しろってな
But there's an important position
ただな ひとつ大事な役目がある
that has to come from our P.E. department,
それを体育科から 出さなきゃならない
because we are the P.E. department.
我々は体育科だからな
The P.E. department!
体育科だぞ
That is the team supervisor.
そう チームの引率だ
Who among you
誰か
will volunteer?
やってくれる人いないか
Our track and field team has been very busy lately. I don't have time.
陸上部は最近バタバタしてて
I don't have time.
無理です
I coach basketball.
俺はバスケ担当なんで
What do I know about football?
サッカーはさっぱりですよ
I can't.
無理です
I don't know how to play any ball games.
私 球技は全然ダメで
I only know rhythmic gymnastics.
新体操しかできません
I just got here.
私 来たばっかりだし
It shouldn't have anything to do with me, right?
関係ないよね
It seems opportunities always go to young people
やっぱりチャンスってのはな
who dare to think and take action.
行動力のある若者に 巡ってくるもんだ
Ms. Lin.
林先生
Your chance to shine has finally arrived.
君の出番が来たぞ
Look.
ほら
This is the newly drafted
これが学校で新しくまとめた
-No way. -list of the football team members.
- 嘘でしょ - サッカー部員の名簿だ
Please review it.
目を通してくれ
This glorious and challenging task
この光栄かつ重大な任務を
will be entrusted to you.
君に任せる
Me?
私がですか
Let's go eat.
行くぞ ご飯だ
Bye.
お先に失礼します
Dir—
主…
Director Qian, you did this on purpose, didn't you?
銭主任はわざとでしょ
Playing dumb?
とぼけて
Pretending not to see me?
私が見えないぷり？
[Crossword Puzzle]
[クロスワード]
"Family Line..."
絶
"Family Line Dying Out"?
絶子絶孫
You haven't left yet?
まだいたのか
You have a good mindset.
メンタルが強い
Do you need me for something?
何か用か？
Come on, grab a chair.
ほら 椅子を持ってきて
Have a seat.
座って話そう
Director Qian.
銭主任
I majored in psychology.
私は心理学専攻なんです
Everyone has their own specialty.
専門も違いますし
Well...
ですから…
Since you're so good at psychology,
心理学をそこまで
I think you're the perfect person
勉強した君だからこそ
to lead the team.
この仕事に向いてるんだよ
It's completely outside my field.
畑違いですよ
Actually, you don't need to worry so much.
そんな心配しなくていい
Let me tell you a secret.
実はな
Actually, No. 8 High School's football team is pretty strong.
八高のサッカー部は 結構強かったんだ
When they were in junior high,
中学時代には
they even won
彼らは一度
the city championship once.
市大会で優勝しているんだぞ
Really?
そうなんですか
Really. I'm not lying to you.
本当だって 嘘じゃない
Let me show you these kids.
この子たちを見てみろ
[Hongjing No. 8 High School Football Team Roster]
[宏景第八高校 サッカー部員リスト]
Look.
ほら
They are all full of energy.
みんな元気があって
Smart and ambitious.
夢も志もある
[Name: Qin Ao] [Name: Lin Lu] [Name: Qi Liang]
[氏名 秦敖][氏名 林鹿] [氏名 祁亮]
And you say you're not lying?
十分嘘じゃない？
Come on, Young Master!
いや 若様
-I've been so loyal to you! -Beautiful.
- 俺はこんなに尽くしたのに - 美人さん
What is it?
俺に何の用？
Honest.
誠実で
I'm a senior in Class 5. My name is Qin Ao.
３年５組 秦敖だ
Qin as in Emperor Qin.
秦は始皇帝の秦
Ao as in Tibetan Mastiff, without the "dog" component.
敖は獒犬の獒 でも犬なしだ
Disciplined.
ルールも守る
That boy has been playing football there all afternoon.
あの男子は 昼からずっとサッカーしてる
He must be skipping class.
きっと授業をサボってるな
They're highly skilled
能力も高いし
and very competitive.
根性だってある
Director Qian,
銭主任
my abilities are limited.
やっぱり私には荷が重いです
I can't take on this responsibility.
この役目は務まらないと思います
I think
ですので
you should find someone else.
他の先生にお願いした方が……
You're still on probation.
君 まだ試用期間中だよな
If you fail to meet the school's expectations,
学校の期待に応えられなかったら
let me tell you,
言っとくけどな
many people around you,
周りの人間も
including me,
もちろん私も
won't be able to help you.
力になれなくなるぞ
Just treat it as taking the kids out
子供たちを連れて
for some outdoor exercise.
ちょっと校外活動に行く そのくらいの気持ちでいい
Actually, the results don't matter.
結果なんて別にどうでもいいんだ
Winning or losing doesn't matter?
勝ち負けは 気にしなくていいんですか
It's just that
ただな
there's not much time left before the match.
試合の日程が少し詰まっててね
It's this Sunday.
今度の日曜なんだ
Don't worry.
でも安心しろ
The school leaders have always been
学校は若い先生のことを
very supportive and helpful to young teachers.
ちゃんと応援してくれるから
How about this?
こうしよう
Tomorrow afternoon,
明日の午後
we will
サッカー部の
meet these kids on the football team
子たちと
formally.
正式に顔合わせをしよう
Tomorrow?
明日ですか？
I've already sent out the notices.
もう連絡は回してある
Really.
本当だ
But there's no getting out
だからな この役目からは
of this job.
逃げられないぞ
Good luck.
頑張れ
So many notices?
通知がこんなに
[Contacts]
[連絡先]
[I'm Winfred]
ウィンフレッドです
Winfred?
ウィンフレッド？
Who is this?
誰よ これ
[Added by searching your phone number]
[電話番号で追加されました]
[Recents]
[着信]
[Agent]
[不動産屋さん]
The number you dialed is busy. Please try again later.
おかけになった電話はただいま 通話中です このまましばらく…
[Creamy Taro Milk Tea with Pudding]
[濃厚タロイモミルクティー]
Let me order a cup of milk tea to calm my nerves.
とりあえず ミルクティーを飲んで落ち着こう
[Brown Sugar Boba Milk Tea]
[黒糖タピオカミルクティー]
Behind this tree.
この木の裏にいるんだ
Behind the tree.
木の裏
Listen to the footsteps.
足音を聞け 足音
-Reload Reload first. -I'm out of ammo.
- まずリロードしろ リロード - 弾切れだ
Reload first. Your high-powered scope won't work.
リロードしろって 高スコじゃ無理だ
Switch to a low-powered scope!
低スコにしろ
Isn't there a low-powered scope here?
低スコープがあるだろ
I don't have a high-powered scope, bro.
高スコを持ってねえんだよ
His teammate will be here in a sec.
仲間来るぞ
You should run first.
逃げろ逃げろ
This way. This way.
こっちだ こっち
-Hello, teacher. -This way!
- 先生 こんにちは - こっちだ
What are you doing?
何してるの？
Studying.
勉強してます…
Relaxing.
リラックスしてます
[Qin Ao, Former Football Team Forward]
[秦敖 元サッカー部の フォワード]
[Lin Lu, Former Football Team Defender]
[林鹿 元サッカー部の ディフェンダー]
[Qi Liang, Former Football Team Defender]
[祁亮 元サッカー部の
Right.
そうです
What are their names?
その２人の名前は？
Do you think I'm stupid?
俺をバカにしてる？
Like I'd tell you their names are Lin Lu and Qi Liang,
こいつらは林鹿と祁亮だと 教えるとでも？
and then let you go tell Jin Laoyao
そしたら 金先生に俺たちが
that we're skipping class to play games here?
サボってゲームしてたって チクるだろ
Lin Lu? Qi Liang?
林鹿 祁亮
[Name: Qin Ao] [Name: Lin Lu] [Name: Qi Liang]
[氏名 秦敖][氏名 林鹿] [氏名 祁亮]
-Boss! -Come on, bro.
- 兄貴 - お前
What's wrong?
どうした
Our names...
名前
Lin Lu.
林鹿くん
How good are you guys at playing football?
あなたたち サッカーは上手いの？
I'm awesome at it.
俺はめちゃくちゃ上手いっす
Qi Liang is also great.
祁亮もかなり上手い
We used to be on the school football team.
俺たち 元サッカー部だからな
What about your boss?
じゃあ あなたたちの兄貴は？
How does he play?
うまいわけ？
Him?
こいつは
He sucks.
下手っすよ
Lin Lu.
林鹿
What are you laughing at?
何を笑ってんだ
You are indeed just average.
実際 そんなに上手くないだろ
Since you were on the school football team,
元サッカー部だったのに
why aren't you playing anymore?
どうして今はやってないの？
What year is this?
今どきサッカーなんて
Football is outdated.
もう流行んないって
It's the era of e-sports now.
今はeスポーツの時代さ
You three,
３人とも
wait for me here.
ここで待ってなさい
Why did you have to say
なんで俺の名前を
my name?
言うんだよ
-Who sucks at football? -Why were you so loud?
- 誰が下手だって？ - あんに大きな声で
-Say it again. -Why?
- もう一回言ってみろ - どうするんだよ
Who sucks at football?
誰が下手だって？
Didn't you say it first?
先に言ったのそっちだろ
-Right? -Who sucks at football?
- お前だろ - 誰が下手なんだよ
Why did you say our names?
なんで俺らの名前まで出すんだよ
-Yeah. -So what if I did?
- そうだよ - 言ったら何だよ
You just had to say our names?
何で俺らまで巻き込むんだ
Let's go!
早く行こうぜ
-The teacher will be back soon. -Where are you going?
- 先生は戻ってくるぞ - どこへ行くの？
Teacher,
先生
ordering takeout at school violates the school rules.
校内でデリバリーは校則違反っすよ
I am a teacher.
私は先生だけど
Then...
あ
Then you can do it.
じゃあ 大丈夫っすね
Director Qian said your team used to be very strong
銭主任から聞いたわ 昔は強かったんでしょ
and even won some championships.
優勝もしたって
Why did you give up?
なのにどうして辞めたの？
Boss. Boss. Boss.
兄貴 兄貴ってば
Teacher!
先生
We didn't win the championship.
俺たちは優勝したことなんてない
We'll always be...
ずっと
runners-up.
準優勝だ
Why bring that up? Let's go.
そんな話はいいだろ 行くぞ
What's wrong with them?
あの子たちはどうしたの？
Hello?
もしもし
Ms. Lin.
林さん
Here's the situation.
実はですね
The previous tenant on the 3rd floor
３階の入居者なんですが
had a minor change of plans.
ちょっと事情が変わりまして
They said they're not renting anymore.
退去することになったんです
What?
退去？
Didn't they already move in yesterday?
昨日もう入居したでしょ？
A mother and son?
母子だったよね
Yes, the mother and son from before.
ええ その母子なんです
They've already moved out.
もう出て行かれまして
Well...
えっ
does that count as a breach of contract?
それって違約にならないの？
Don't worry.
まあまあ 落ち着いてください
I've already found you a new tenant.
もう新しい入居者は 見つけてありますから
The rent is double the original amount.
しかも家賃は倍ですよ
Thanks for your hard work.
それはどうも
It's nothing.
いえいえ
It's just that the new tenant has...
ただですね 新しい入居者さんから
a tiny request.
ちょっとしたお願いがありまして
What is it?
何？
Well...
バスタブを
He needs a bathtub.
付けたいそうです
A bathtub?
バスタブ？
How can a bathtub be installed in my apartment?
うちの部屋にそんなの無理でしょ
The bathtub has already arrived.
実はもう届いてまして
The workers are installing it now.
今まさに工事中です
What?
は？
Wait for me to get back.
ちょっと待って 今帰るから
Here.
はい
Ms. Lin.
林さん
1,100.
２万２千円です
This bathtub is imported from Italy.
このバスタブ イタリア製ですよ
Looks premium, right?
高級感あるでしょう
Don't worry.
ご安心ください
The tenant paid
工事費は全部
for the installation of this bathtub.
入居者さんが持ちです
This is a good thing for us.
こちらに損はありませんから
Ms. Lin.
林さん
This tenant is very sincere.
それにこの方は かなり本気なんですよ
You know, the market competition is fierce now.
今どき賃貸市場も厳しいですし
Your apartment wouldn't rent out at all.
正直言ってこの部屋 なかなか借り手がつきませんから
But you shouldn't have done it without telling me.
だからって 勝手に 決めていい話じゃないでしょ
What if this bathtub leaks
もし水漏れして
and the water gets into my room?
うちまで被害が出たらどうするの？
I called you this morning.
朝ちゃんと電話しましたよ
You never answered.
でも出なかったじゃないですか
The tenant was in a hurry
入居者さんは急いでるし
and willing to pay more.
家賃も上乗せしてくれるし
So I agreed first.
それで先にＯＫしちゃったんです
It's almost 6 PM.
あっ もうすぐ６時で
I'm in a bit of a rush.
ちょっと次の予定があるんで
So I'll get going now.
失礼しますね
Ms. Lin,
林さん
let's keep in touch!
何かあればまたご連絡ください
Who exactly is the landlord here?
一体どっちが大家なのよ
Where did this weirdo come from?
変な人
If he can afford an imported bathtub,
輸入物のバスタブが買えるなら
why rent my apartment?
なんで私の部屋を借りるの？
Hello, Ms. Lin.
こんにちは 林さん
The QR Code?
ＱＲコード男？
I am your new tenant,
新しく入居する
Wang Fa.
王法だ
♪ There's nothing to fear ♪
♪ 何も怖くない ♪
♪ Because you're with me ♪
♪ 君がいるから ♪
♪ The light shimmers ♪
♪ 微かな光が交差して ♪
♪ Brilliant as stars ♪
♪ 星のように煌めく ♪
♪ Running towards you ♪
♪ 君の元へ駆け出して ♪
♪ I keep moving fearlessly ♪
♪ 恐れず前へ進もう ♪
♪ Walk side by side ♪
♪肩を並べて♪
♪ Become ourselves ♪
♪ ありのままの僕らへ ♪